searchlotto.co.uk 2018-11-17

# Privacy Policy :: Search Lotto :: Play the National Lottery for free by searching the web

Updated as of 23/05/2018

**_Our Privacy Policy_**

Search Lotto is committed to protecting your privacy and promise to collect, process and share your data safely and securely when you use the Search Lotto app or website. Our Privacy Policy tells you how we do this and what your rights are. Any personal data processed in line with our Privacy Policy is controlled by us, as the data controller.

**_Our Promise_**

**Transparency** – We will always tell you what data we’re collecting about you and how we use it.

**Secure** – We are committed to always follow industry best practices to ensure your data is stored safely and securely. We protect the confidentiality, accuracy and availability of the information we collect about you.

**Control** – We will always give you control over the marketing you receive from us. You can choose the types of messages you receive and whether you want to stop receiving marketing communications.

**_The Data We Collect About You_**

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows: 

  * **Identity and Contact Data** which includes title, first name, last name, date of birth, gender, home address and email address.
  * **Contact Data** which includes home address and email address.
  * **Financial Data** which includes bank account details.
  * **Technical Data** which includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this Site.
  * **Profile Data** which includes your username and password, Internet searches you perform and your preferences.
  * **Transaction Data** which includes payments made to you, details of entries issued to you and the outcomes of these entries.
  * **Usage Data** which includes information about how you use our Site, products and services.
  * **Marketing and Communications Data** which includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us.

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific Site feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

Except in limited circumstances which will be made clear to you, we do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

**_Purpose For Which We Will Use Your Personal Data_**

We have set out below a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

**What is a legitimate interest?**

**Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service and the best and most secure experience on our Site. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party. If you fail to provide personal data that we require for the performance of a contract with you we cannot enter into a contract with you for the provision of our services.

| 

Activity / Purpose

| 

Type of Data

| 

Why we use your data  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Provide our service to you. This includes but is not limited to:

  * Providing search results
  * Allocating lottery entries to you
  * Checking lottery entries allocated to you
  * Managing payments for winning lottery entries via third parties such as PayPal or BACS

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Financial

(d) Technical

(e) Profile  
(f) Transaction

| 

Performance of a contract with you.  
  
2

| 

Answering and processing any claims or enquiries you may raise with us

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Financial

(d) Technical

(e) Profile

(f) Transaction 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate Interests to provide the most effective service to the members.  
  
3

| 

Utilising fraud prevention measures in order to protect the business from fraudulent activity and any resulting consequences. 

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Financial

(d) Technical

(e) Profile

(f) Transaction 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests to prevent fraud.  
  
4

| 

Managing our relationship with you, for example: 

  * Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy
  * Updating your details on our system in order to keep our records updated

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Marketing and Communications

(e) Technical 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests of updating customer details and preferences.   
  
5

| 

To administer and protect our business and this Site such as: 

  * troubleshooting
  * data analysis
  * testing
  * system maintenance
  * support
  * reporting and hosting of data

in order for the efficient running of the Site, provision of administration and IT services, network security and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise.

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

(d) Financial

(e) Transactional

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests of Site security.  
  
**Third Party Marketing**

We will never sell your personal data to any company outside of Search Media Ltd for marketing purposes.

**Cookies**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this Site will become inaccessible or not function properly.

**Change of Purpose**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

**_Disclosures of Your Personal Data_**

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out above:

  * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

**_Data Security_**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

**_Data Retention_**

**How Long Will You Use My Data For?**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

Details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are available in our retention policy which you can request from us by contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

**_Your Legal Rights_**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data.

You have the right to:

**Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

**Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

**Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

**Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

**Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

**No Fee Usually Required**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**What We May Need From You**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**Time Limit To Respond**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
